boschrexroth.com 2019-09-15

# Privacy Statement | Bosch Rexroth AG

Bosch Rexroth AG (hereinafter "Bosch Rexroth AG" or "We" or "Us") welcomes you to our internet pages and mobile applications (together also referred to as "Online Offers"). We thank you for your interest in our company and our products. 

## 1\. The Bosch Rexroth AG respects your privacy

The protection of your privacy throughout the course of processing personal data as well as the security of all business data is an important concern to us. We process personal data that was gathered during your visit of our Online Offers confidentially and only in accordance with statutory regulations.

Data protection and information security are included in our corporate policy.

## 2\. Controller

Bosch Rexroth AG is the controller responsible for the processing of your data, exceptions are outlined in this data protection notice. 

Our contact details are as follows: 

Bosch Rexroth AG

Zum Eisengießer 1

97816 Lohr am Main

**Executive Board:**

Rolf Najork, Vorsitzender, Dr. Markus Forschner, Reinhard Schäfer, Dr. Marc Wucherer 

**Chairman of the Supervisory Board**

Christoph Kübel

**Your contact to Bosch Rexroth AG**

Company’s headquarters

+49 9352 18 0

**Registration**

Amtsgericht Stuttgart HRB 23192

**VAT ID No**

DE813 084 274

## 3\. Collection, processing and usage of personal data

## **3.1 Processed categories of data**

At least the following categories of data are processed:

• Communication data (e.g. name, telephone, e-mail, address, IP address)

For further details, please refer to the respective offers listed below.

**3.2 Principles**

Personal data consists of all information related to an identified or identifiable natural person, this includes, e.g. names, addresses, phone numbers, email addresses and contractual master data, which is an expression of a person's identity.

We collect, process and use personal data (including IP addresses) only when there is either a statutory legal basis to do so or if you have given your consent to the processing or use of personal data concerning this matter, e.g. by means of registration. 

**3.3 Processing purposes and legal basis**

We as well as the service providers commissioned by us, process your personal data for the following processing purposes:

**3.3.1 Provision of these Online Offers**

(Legal basis: Legitimate interest on our part in direct marketing as long as this occurs in accordance with data protection and competition law and / or fulfillment of contractual obligations).

**3.3.2 Resolving service disruptions as well as for security reasons**

(Legal basis: Fulfillment of our legal obligations within the scope of data security and legitimate interest in resolving service disruptions as well as in the protection of our offers).

**3.3.3 Self-promotion and promotion by others as well as market research and reach analysis done within the scope statutorily permitted or based on consent**

(Legal basis: Consent / legitimate interest on our part in direct marketing if in accordance with data protection and competition law).

**3.3.4 Safeguarding and defending our rights**

(Legal basis: Legitimate interest on our part for safeguarding and defending our rights).

For further details, please refer to the respective offers listed below.

**3.4 Registration**

The use of some services may require prior registration.

Within the scope of the registration, we collect necessary personal data for the use of the services (e.g. first name, last name, email address) as well as further data on voluntary basis, if applicable. Mandatory information is marked with an *.

The data provided by you will only be stored for the respective registration process and used exclusively for the performance of the services provided. For further details, please refer to the respective offers listed below. 

Please see our “Terms of Registration and Use for the services of Bosch Rexroth AG”.

**3.5 Log files**

Each time you use the internet, your browser is transmitting certain information, which we store in so-called log files.

We save log files for a short period of time to determine service disruptions and for security reasons (e.g., to investigate attack attempts) and delete them afterwards. Log files which need to be maintained for evidence purposes are excluded from deletion until the respective incident is resolved and may, on a case-by-case basis, be passed on to investigating authorities.

Log files are also used for analysis purposes (without the IP address or without the complete IP address). Also see module “Self-promotion and promotion by others as well as market research and reach analysis done within the scope statutorily permitted or based on consent”.

In log files, in particular the following information is saved:

• IP address (Internet Protocol address) of the end-device from which the Online Offer is accessed,

• Internet address of the website from which the Online Offer was accessed (so called origin or referrer URL),

• The name of the service provider by whom the Online Offer is accessed,

• File names or information that were accessed,

• Access time, date and access duration,

• Transmitted data volume,

• http status code (for example, request was successful or request failed)

**3.6 Children**

This Online Offer is not meant for children under 16 years of age.

**3.7 Data transfer to other controllers**

Principally, your personal data is forwarded to other controllers only if required for the fulfillment of a contractual obligation, or if we ourselves, or a third party, have a legitimate interest in the data transfer, or if you have given your consent. Particulars on the legal bases can be found in the Section - “Purposes of Processing and Legal Bases”. Third parties may also be other companies of the Bosch group. When data is transferred to third parties based on a justified interest, this is explained in this data protection notice.

Additionally, data may be transferred to other controllers when we are obliged to do so due to statutory regulations or enforceable administrative or judicial orders.

**3.7.1 Service providers (general)**

We involve external service providers with tasks such as sales and marketing services, contract management, programming, data hosting and hotline services. We have chosen those service providers carefully and monitor them on a regular basis, especially regarding their diligent handling of and protection of the data that they store. All service providers are obliged to maintain confidentiality and to comply to the statutory provisions. Service providers may also be other Bosch group companies.

**3.8 Transfer to recipients outside the EEA**

We might transfer personal data to recipients located outside the EEA into so-called third countries. In such cases, prior to the transfer we ensure that either the data recipient provides an appropriate level of data protection (e.g. due to a decision of adequacy by the European Commission for the respective country or due to the agreement based on so-called EU model clauses with the recipient) or that you have consented to the transfer.

You are entitled to receive an overview of third country recipients and a copy of the specifically agreed-to provisions securing an appropriate level of data protection. For this purpose, please use the statements made in the “Contact” section.

**3.9 Duration of storage, retention periods**

Principally, we store your data for as long as it is necessary to render our Online Offers and connected services or for as long as we have a justified interest in storing the data (e.g. we might still have a justified interest in postal marketing even after fulfillment of our contractual obligations). In all other cases we delete your personal data with the exception of data we are obliged to store for the fulfillment of legal obligations (e.g. due to retention periods under the tax and commercial codes we are obliged to have documents such as contracts and invoices available for a certain period of time).

**3.10 Data processing under other legal regulations**

We collect data based on other legal regulations. These include, for example, regulations for export controls, EC regulations (terrorist list screening), military, known consignors (air freight security law), taxes, ILSG, general equality law, labour law and many more. We treat the data according to the specifications of the respective legal regulation and analogously their storage obligations. Personal data will be deleted immediately after the end of the storage obligations.

## 4\. Communities

We offer you the opportunity of becoming a member of one of our communities. 

The public profile of a community member only shows the nickname, acquired badges (trophies), the rank and the last user interactions. The e-mail address or other personal data are not visible.

All other data, which is generated by you in the communities, e.g. by creating, comments or pictures, are automatically publicly accessible and will be linked to your user profile.

A special case of this are so-called private communities, where only registered members can enter the community and see the content.

Typical community elements in which community members interact and/or create content are for example Forum, Blog, Tribal Knowledge Base (Wiki), Question & Answers and Idea Exchange.

## 5\. Usage of cookies

In the context of our online service, cookies and tracking mechanisms may be used. 

Cookies are small text files that may be stored on your device when visiting our online service. 

We operate some of our websites, only with technically required cookies. On these websites no cookie manager dialogue is in use.

Tracking is possible using different technologies. In particular, we process information using pixel technology and/or during log file analysis. On these websites a cookie manager dialogue is in use.

**5.1 Categories**

We distinguish between cookies that are mandatorily required for the technical functions of the online service and such cookies and tracking mechanisms that are not mandatorily required for the technical function of the online service. 

It is generally possible to use the online service without any cookies that serve non-technical purposes.

**5.1.1 Technically required cookies**

By technically required cookies we mean cookies without those the technical provision of the online service cannot be ensured. These include e.g. cookies that store data to ensure smooth reproduction of video or audio footage.

Such cookies will be deleted when you leave the website.

**5.1.2 Cookies and tracking mechanisms that are technically not required**

We only use such cookies and tracking mechanisms if you have given us your prior consent in each case. We distinguish between two sub-categories with regard to these cookies and tracking mechanisms:

**5.2 Convenience cookies**

These cookies facilitate operation and thus allow you to browse our online service more comfortably; e.g. your language settings may be included in these cookies.

**5.3 Marketing cookies and tracking mechanisms**

\- General

By using marketing cookies and tracking mechanisms we and our partners are able to show you offerings based on your interests, resulting from an analysis of your user behaviour:

\- Statistics:

By using statistical tools, we measure e.g. the number of your page views. 

\- Conversion tracking:

Our conversion tracking partners place a cookie on your computer ("conversion cookie") if you accessed our website via an advertisement of the respective partner. Normally these cookies are no longer valid after 30 days. If you visit certain pages of our website and the cookie has not yet expired, we and the relevant conversion partner can recognize that a certain user clicked on the advertisement and thereby was redirected to our website. The information obtained by means of the conversion cookie serves the purpose of compiling conversion statistics and recording the total number of users who clicked on the respective advertisement and were redirected to a website with a conversion tracking tag.

\- Social plugins

Some of the pages of our online service involve content and services of other providers (e.g. Facebook, Twitter) which also may use cookies and active modules. For more details regarding social plugins please refer to the section on “social plugins”.

\- Retargeting

These tools create user profiles by means of advertising cookies or third-party advertising cookies so called "web beacons" (invisible graphics that are also called pixels or tracking pixels), or by means of comparable technologies. These are used for interest-based advertising and to control the frequency with which the user looks at certain advertisements. The relevant provider is the controller responsible for the processing of data in connection with the tool. The providers of the tools might disclose information also to third parties for the purposes mentioned above. Please note the data protection notices of the relevant provider in this context.

\- Cross-Device-Tracking

In this case, based on a pseudonymous user ID, a pseudonymous profile of the user is created with information from the use of different devices.

Please note that using the tools might include transfer of your data to recipients outside of the EEA where there is no adequate level of data protection pursuant to the GDPR (e.g. the USA). For more details in this respect please refer to the following description of the individual marketing tools.

**5.3.1 Name:** WebTrends

**Provider:** WebTrends Inc., 851 SW 6th Ave., Suite 1600, Portland Oregon 97206, USA

**Function:** Analyses user behaviour (page views, number of visitors and visits, downloads)

**5.3.2 Name:** Monetate

**Provider:** Monetate Inc., 100 Crosby Street #402, New York, NY 10012, USA

**Function:** Cookie can trace user behaviour across websites, UX testing

**5.3.3 Name:** Google Analytics 

**Provider:** Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA

**Function:** Analyses user behaviour (page views, number of visitors and visits, downloads), UX testing

**5.3.4 Name:** Tealium 

**Provider:** Tealium Inc., 11095 Torreyana Road San Diego, CA 92121

**Function:** Creates segments and profiles in real time, tag management

**5.3.5 Name:** New Relic 

**Provider:** New Relic Inc. 111 SW 5th Ave 2700, Portland, OR 97204 

**Function:** Measurement of website availability and downtime

**5.4 Management of cookies and tracking mechanisms**

You can manage your cookie and tracking mechanism settings in the browser and/or our privacy settings.

Note: The settings you have made refer only to the browser used in each case.

**5.4.1 Deactivation of all cookies**

If you wish to deactivate all cookies, please deactivate cookies in your browser settings. Please note that this may affect the functionality of the website.

**5.4.2 Management of your settings with regard to cookies and tracking mechanisms not required technically**

When visiting our websites, you will be asked in a cookie layer whether you consent to our using of any convenience cookies, marketing cookies or tracking mechanisms, respectively. 

In our privacy settings, you may withdraw the consent with effect for the future or grant your consent at a later point in time.

## 6\. Social Plugins

In our Online Offers we use so-called social plugins from various social networks. They are individually described in this section.

When using plugins, your internet browser creates a direct connection to the respective social networks’ server. This way, the respective provider receives the information that your internet browser accessed from the respective site of our Online Offers - even if you do not have a user account with this provider or are currently not logged into your account. Log files (including the IP address) are, in this case, directly transmitted from your internet browser to a server of the respective provider and might be stored there. The provider or its server may be located outside the EU or the EEA (e.g. in the USA).

The plugins are standalone extensions by social network providers. For this reason, we are unable to influence the scope of data collected and stored by them.

Purpose and scope of the collection, the continued processing and usage of data by the social network as well as your respective rights and setting options to protect your privacy can be found by consulting the respective social network's data protection notices.

In case you do not wish social network providers to receive and, if applicable, store or use data, you should not use the respective plugins. 

**6.1 Facebook plugins**

Facebook is operated under [www.facebook.com](http://www.facebook.com/) by Facebook Inc., 1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA, and under [www.facebook.de](http://www.facebook.de/) by Facebook Ireland Limited, Hanover Reach, 5-7 Hanover Quay, Dublin 2, Ireland ("Facebook"). Find an overview over Facebook's plugins and their appearance here: <https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins> , find information on data protection at Facebook here: <http://www.facebook.com/policy.php> .

**6.2 Twitter plugins**

Twitter is operated by Twitter Inc., 1355 Market St, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA ("Twitter"). Find an overview over Twitter's plugins and their appearance here: <https://developer.twitter.com/> , find information on data protection at Twitter here: <https://twitter.com/privacy> .

**6.3 Google+ plugins**

Google+ is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA ("Google"). Find an overview over Google's plugins and their appearance here: <https://developers.google.com/+/plugins> , find information on data protection at Google+ here: <http://www.google.com/intl/de/+/policy/+1button.html> .

**6.4 Pinterest plugins**

Pinterest is operated by Pinterest Inc., 808 Brennan St, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA ("Pinterest"). Find an overview over Pinterest's plugins and their appearance here: <https://developers.pinterest.com/tools/widget-builder/> , find information on data protection at Pinterest here: <https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy> .

**6.5 Instagram plugins**

Instagram is operated by Instagram LLC., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA ("Instagram"). Find an overview over Instagram's plugins and their appearance here: <http://blog.instagram.com/post/36222022872/introducing-instagram-badges> , find information on data protection at Instagram here: <https://help.instagram.com/155833707900388/> .

**6.6 E-Mail to a friend**

Your e-mails distributed will only be saved until the sending process is completed and then deleted.

**6.7 Share Button**

Only when you actively click on the share button data will be sent to the operators of the social media channels. No data is sent to the operators of the social media channels beforehand - not even in an anonymous form.

## 7\. Usage of our mobile applications

In addition to our websites we offer mobile applications ("Apps"), which you can download to your mobile device. Apart from the data collected on websites, we collect additional personal data through our apps that specifically result from the usage of the respective app. This is subject to your prior express consent.

If our apps collect or process personal data deviating from this Data Protection Notice, please refer to the respective offers listed below.

## **7.1 Processing of the advertising identifier / advertising ID**

For advertising purposes, we use, given your consent, the so-called "advertising identifier" (IDFA) for iOS devices and the so-called advertising ID for Android devices. These are not permanent identification numbers for a certain terminal device provided by iOS or Android. The data which are collected is not brought together with other device-related information. We use identification numbers to provide you with personalized advertisements and to analyze your usage. When you activate (for iOS devices) the option "no ad tracking" in the device settings under "Privacy" - "Advertisements" or (for Android devices) activate "deactivate interest-based advertisements" in the Google settings under "Advertisements", we can only perform the following measures: Measuring your interaction with banners by counting the number of displays of a banner without clicks ("frequency capping"), click rate, assessment of unique usage ("unique user") and security measures, fraud combating and troubleshooting. In the device settings, you are always able to delete your IDFA or advertising ID ("reset ad ID"); a new identification number is generated then which is not combined with data collected earlier. We advise you that you might be unable to use all functions of our app when you restrict the usage of the respective identification number.

## **7.2 Data processing by App Store operators**

We do not collect data, and it is beyond our responsibility, when data, such as username, email address and individual device identifier are transferred to an app store (e.g., Google Play by Google, App Store by Apple, Galaxy Apps Store by Samsung) when downloading the respective App. We are unable to influence this data collection and further processing by the App Store as controller.

## 8\. YouTube

Our Online Offers use the YouTube video platform which is operated by YouTube, LLC, 901 Cherry Ave. San Bruno, CA 94066, USA („YouTube”). YouTube is a platform which allows the playback of audio and video files.

When you access a respective site of our Online Offers that contains an embedded YouTube player, this creates a connection to YouTube so that the video or audio file can be transmitted and played back. In doing so, data is transferred to YouTube as a data controller. We are not responsible for the processing of such data by YouTube.

Additional information on the scope and purpose of collected data, on further processing and usage of data by YouTube, on your rights and the privacy options available to be chosen by you, can be found in YouTube's data protection notice.

## 9\. Communication tools on social media platforms

We use on our social media platform (e.g. twitter) communication tools to process your messages sent via this social media platform and to offer you support.

When sending a message via our social media platform the message is processed to handle your query (and if necessary additional data, which we receive from the social media provider in connection with this message as your name or files).

In addition we can analyze these data in an aggregated and anonymized form in order to understand better how our social media platform is used. 

We will forward the personal data you provide to the Bosch legal entity responsible for the processing of your query (for example, in the event your query refers to a product that is distributed by another Bosch legal entity). The legal basis for the processing of your data is our legitimate interest (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f GDPR) or, if applicable, an existing contractual relationship (Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b GDPR). The processed personal data is deleted 180 days at the latest after receipt of your message.

## 10\. External links

Our Online Offers may contain links to third party - internet pages – by providers who are not related to us. Upon clicking on the link, we have no influence on the collecting, processing and use of personal data possibly transmitted by clicking on the link to the third party (such as the IP address or the URL of the site on which the link is located) as the conduct of third parties is naturally beyond our supervision. We do not assume responsibility for the processing of personal data by third parties.

## 11\. Security

Our employees and the companies providing services on our behalf, are obliged to confidentiality and to compliance with the applicable data protection laws.

We take all necessary technical and organizational measures to ensure an appropriate level of security and to protect your data that are administrated by us especially from the risks of unintended or unlawful destruction, manipulation, loss, change or unauthorized disclosure or unauthorized access. Our security measures are, pursuant to technological progress, constantly being improved.

## 12\. User rights

To enforce your rights, please use the details provided in the “Contact” section. In doing so, please ensure that an unambiguous identification of your person is possible.

**Right to information and access**

You have the right to obtain confirmation from us about whether or not your personal data is being processed, and, if this is the case, access to your personal data. 

**Right to correction and deletion**

You have the right to obtain the rectification of inaccurate personal data concerning yourself without undue delay from us. Taking into account the purposes of the processing, you have the right to have incomplete personal data completed, including by means of providing a supplementary statement. This does not apply to data that underlies the legal obligation to a statutory retention period to store. If access to such data is not required, however, its processing is restricted (see the following).

**Restriction of processing**

You have the right to demand for – as far as statutory requirements are fulfilled – restriction of the processing of your data. 

**Objection to direct marketing:**

Additionally, you may object to the processing of your personal data for direct marketing purposes at any time. Please take into account that due to organizational reasons, there might be an overlap between your objection and the usage of your data within the scope of a campaign which is already running.

**Objection to data processing based on the legal basis of “justified interest“**

In addition, you have the right to object to the processing of your personal data at any time, insofar as this is based on a justified interest. We will then terminate the processing of your data, unless we demonstrate compelling legitimate reasons according to legal requirements, which predominate your rights.

**Withdrawal of consent**

In case you consented to the processing of your data, you have the right to revoke this consent at any time with effect for the future. The legality of data processing prior to your revocation remains unchanged.

Subscriptions can be withdrawn via the link mentioned in the subscription, if applicable in the settings of the respective Online Offer. Alternatively, please contact us using the information in the section “Contact”.

**Data portability**

You are entitled to receive data that you have provided to us in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format or – if technically feasible – to demand that we transfer those data to a third party.

**12.1 Right of complaint with supervisory authority**

You have the right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority. You can appeal to the supervisory authority, which is responsible for your place of residence or your state of residency, or to the supervisory authority responsible for us. This is:

Bayerisches Landesamt für Datenschutzaufsicht (BayLDA)

<https://www.lda.bayern.de/en/index.html>

## 13\. Changes to the Data Protection Notice

We reserve the right to change our security and data protection measures if this is required due to technical development. In such cases, we will amend our data protection notice accordingly. Please, therefore, notice the current version of our data protection notice, as this is subject to change.

## 14\. Contact

If you wish to contact us, please find us at the address stated in the "Controller" section.

To assert your rights and to notify data protection incidents please use the following link:

[https://www.bkms-system.net/bkwebanon/report/clientInfo?cin=18rbds19&language=eng](https://www.bkms-system.net/bkwebanon/report/clientInfo?cin=18rbds19&language=eng "https://www.bkms-system.net/bkwebanon/report/clientInfo?cin=18rbds19&language=eng")

For suggestions and complaints regarding the processing of your personal data we recommend that you contact our data protection officer:

Data Protection Officer

Information Security and Privacy (C/ISP)

Robert Bosch GmbH

Postfach 30 02 20

70442 Stuttgart

GERMANY

or

_Effective date: 2019-04-01_
